grana.com 2018-06-29

# privacy policy | Grana

Welcome to the Grana Group Limited (Grana) privacy notice.

Grana respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

Please also use the _Glossary_ to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

* ### Important Information And Who We Are

#### Purpose of this Privacy Notice

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Grana collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you sign up to our website, purchase goods and services or take part in any promotions.

Grana collects your information in an effort to enhance and personalize your shopping experience. This information allows us to communicate with our customers about our products, services and promotions.

The privacy notice described below covers the entire Grana website (“the Site,” “we,” “us,” or “our”). Phrases such as “you,” “your” and other similar expressions refer to our customers, or the specific users of this Site. By visiting and using the Site, you accept the practices described in this privacy notice.

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

#### Controller

Grana Group International, a Company which is incorporated in Cayman Islands is our parent company and the controller and responsible for your personal data and this website. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of Grana Group International and its subsidiary Grana Group Limited, a company which is incorporated in Hong Kong (Grana Group). When we mention “Grana”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice we are referring to the relevant company in the Grana Group responsible for processing your data.

If you need to reach us by mail, our best contact address is: 11 Floor, Tin Fung Industrial Mansion, 63 Wong Chuk Hang Road, Wong Chuk Hang, Hong Kong. 

If you have questions or suggestions regarding our privacy standards or anything else please email [cheetahs@grana.com](mailto:cheetahs@grana.com).

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the relevant supervisory authority for data protection issues. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the authorities so please contact us in the first instance.

#### Third parties

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

* ### Collected Data About You

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier, title, date of birth and gender.

  * **Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.

  * **Financial Data** includes bank account and payment card details.

  * **Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.

  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.

  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.

  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, products and services.

  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

#### If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

* ### How is your personal data collected

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

**Direct interactions** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * apply for our products or services;

  * create an account on our website;

  * subscribe to our service or publications;

  * request marketing to be sent to you;

  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or

  * give us some feedback.

**Automated technologies or interactions** As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy below for further details.

**Third parties or publicly available sources** We may receive Technical data about you from the following third parties:

  * Analytics providers: Google based outside the EU. Klaviyo based outside the EU.

  * Advertising networks: Facebook based outside the EU, and Google based outside the EU.

  * Search information providers such as Google based outside the EU.

  * Social platforms such as Facebook based outside the EU. Instagram based outside the EU.

Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Stripe based outside the EU, and Paypal based outside the EU.

Identity, Contact Data, Technical Data, Profile Data, Marketing and Communications Data and Usage Data from data brokers or aggregators such as Stitch Data based outside the EU.

Identity, Contact Data, Transaction Data, Profile Data, Marketing and Communications Data, Technical Data and Usage Data from data storage providers such as Amazon Web Services based outside the EU.

### How We Use Your Personal Data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.

  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by Contacting us.

#### Purposes for which we will use your personal data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please Contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

Purpose/Activity | Type of data | Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer | Identity, Contact, Technical, Marketing and Communications Data | Performance of a contract with you  
To process and deliver your order including: 

Manage payments, fees and charges.

Collect and recover money owed to us

| Identity, Contact, Financial, Transaction, Marketing and Communications and Profile Data | 

Performance of a contract with you

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)  
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| Identity, Contact, Marketing and Communications and Profile Data | 

Performance of a contract with you

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To enable you to partake in a promotion, competition or complete a survey | Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, and Marketing and Communications Data | 

Performance of a contract with you

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | Identity, Contact, and Technical Data | 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, Marketing and Communications, and Technical Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | Technical, and Usage Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
#### Marketing

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing, advertising and promotions. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms

##### Promotional Offers From Us

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

##### Opting Out

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by Contacting us at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, product/service experience or other transactions.

##### Cookies

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see the Cookie section below for more details.

##### Change Of Purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please Contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

* ### Disclosures Of Your Personal Data

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

  * Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.

  * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.

  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

* ### International Transfers

For those of you located in the European Economic Area (EEA), we located outside the EAA in Hong Kong so any data collected will transfer outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

When we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring all your personal data is transferred via a secure transfer protocol such as Secure Hypertext Transfer Protocol. 

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

* ### Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

* ### Data Retention

#### How Long Will You Use My Personal Data For?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

You can request details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data by Contacting us.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure in the Glossary further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

* ### Your Legal Rights

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please click on the links below to find out more about these rights:

  * Request access to your personal data

  * Request correction of your personal data

  * Request erasure of your personal data

  * Object to processing of your personal data

  * Request restriction of processing your personal data

  * Request transfer of your personal data

  * Right to withdraw consent

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please Contact us.

#### What We May Need From You

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

#### Time Limit To Respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

* ### Cookies

#### What are cookies

As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or 'break' certain elements of the sites functionality.

#### How We Use Cookies

We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

#### Disabling cookies

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

#### The cookies we set

If you create an account with us then we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards to remember your site preferences when logged out.

We use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in.

This site offers newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.

This site offers e-commerce or payment facilities and some cookies are essential to ensure that your order is remembered between pages so that we can process it properly.

From time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. These surveys may use cookies to remember who has already taken part in a survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.

When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.

In order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences.

#### Third party cookies

This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official [Google Analytics](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage) page.

Third party analytics are used to track and measure usage of this site so that we can continue to produce engaging content. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site or pages you visit which helps us to understand how we can improve the site for you.

We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including Facebook and Instagram, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

* ### Modification of Policies and Your Duty to Inform us of Changes

This version was last updated on 25 May 2018 and historic versions can be obtained by contacting us.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us and please don’t hesitate to Contact us with any questions.

* ### Glossary

#### Lawful basis

Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by Contacting us

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

#### Third parties

##### Internal Third Parties

Other companies in the Grana Group acting as joint controllers or processor and who are based in Cayman Islands and Hong Kong and provide IT and system administration services and undertake leadership reporting.

##### External Third Parties

  * Service providers acting as processors based in United States who provide IT and system administration and data storage services.

  * Fulfilment online services, and fulfilment providers based in Hong Kong, United Kingdom, and United States which together provides warehouse and order fulfilment services.

  * Advertising providers acting as processors based in Finland, and United States who provide advertising platforms to reach out to you and provide information about our products and services. 

  * Online services as a joint controller based in United States who provide data storage, analysis of your data to study how you use our products/services, to grow our business and to inform and execute our marketing strategy.

#### Your legal rights

You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent** at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
